( GROUP MURMURING ) Be with me Lord , in my hour of need .
MAN : " Nor for the pestilence that walketh in darkness .
Nor for the destruction that wasteth at noonday . "
( GROUP MURMURING ) Be with me Lord , in my hour of need .
MAN : " Because thou hast made the Lord , which is my refuge ,
even the most high , thy habitation . "
GROUP : Be with me Lord , in my hour of need .
MAN : " There shall no evil befall thee ,
neither shall any plague come nigh thy dwelling . "
GROUP : Be with me Lord , in my hour of need .
MAN : " For he shall give his angels charge over thee ,
to keep thee in all thy ways . "
GROUP : Be with me Lord , in my hour of need .
Let 's take a little break , shall we ?
Hon ... Are you feeling all right ?
Yeah , I 'm fine .
( SIGHS ) I just can 't remember one quite like this .
- He should try and get some sleep . - Yeah . Here you go .
- Oh , I 'll take him , Mr. Glatzel . - Huh ?
Yeah .
Thank you .
- Thank you , Ame . - No problem . Come on , buddy .
- He can 't take much more of this . - He won 't have to .
Things will move quickly now that the exorcism 's been approved .
Father Gordon 's already on his way .
You 're one brave kid , you know ?
I was a little runt growing up , so ...
I know what it 's like to be picked on .
But ...
But , that was nothing compared to what you 're going through .
I don 't feel very brave .
Being brave doesn 't mean you 're not scared .
It means you are scared but you hang in there .
It 's gonna be all right ...
I won 't let anything happen to you .
I promise .
Arne ? When are you gonna ask my sister to marry you ?
( LAUGHS LIGHTLY )
I don 't know what you 're talking about .
- Come on . - No , I don 't , I ... ( CHUCKLES )
( CAR APPROACHES OUTSIDE )
( CRICKETS CHIRRING )
- ( KNOCKING ON DOOR ) - ( GASPS )
( LOUD POUNDING )
- ( LOUD THUD ) - ( DOORKNOB RATTLING )
( DOOR CONTINUES RATTLING )
( RATTLING STOPS )
( FAINT CLICK )
( BREATH SHAKING )
( FAUCET HANDLES CREAKING )
( SCREAMING ) No ! Help me !
No , no , no ! No , no , no !
( SCREAMING )
- David ! - GIRL : David ! Where is he ?
( GLASS SHATTERS )
- David ! - ( DAVID SCREAMING )
( PANTING )
DAD : What 's happening , buddy ? Are you okay ?
David , what 's going on ?
David ?
- ( DAVID SCREAMS ) - ( ALL YELLING , SCREAMING )
( DAD SCREAMING )
- No ! - ( DAVID SCREAMING )
Father , we need to do this , right now !
Okay , let 's get him down to the car and we 'll drive him to the church .
- No , Father . Right now . - ( DAVID SHRIEKING )
( SHRIEKING CONTINUES )
No ! No !
( GRUNTING LOUDLY ) No !
- ( GRUNTS ) - ( DAVID YELLING )
Grab his arms , don 't let go .
( FERAL GROWLING )
" Save your servant who trusts in you , my God .
Let him find in you , Lord ,
a fortified tower in the face of the enemy . "
WOMAN : " Put on the full armor of God ,
that ye may be able to stand against the wiles of the Devil .
Against the powers of the darkness of this world .
Against wickedness . "
( GASPS )
( DAVID SCREECHING )
Lorraine , what 's wrong ?
I 'm fine .
Lorraine !
- ( WATER HISSING ) - Lord ! Send him aid
from your Holy place and watch over him from Sion .
- ( WATER HISSING ) - ( GROWLING )
Lord , heed my prayer .
- Lord ! - ( BONES CRACKING )
( GUTTURAL GROWL )
( LOW RUMBLING )
( PLATES CLATTERING )
( GRUNTS )
( DEEP CACKLING )
No . Father !
( GIRL SHRIEKS )
- ( DEMON GROWLING ) - ( GROANS )
WOMAN : Father !
- Where 's your first aid kit ? - It 's in the kitchen !
I 'm on it !
Ed , hurry up !
( DEMON ROARING )
- Hurry , Ed ! - ( GROANS WEAKLY )
Ed . Ed , hurry !
" Ergo , draco maledicte et omnis ...
( CACKLING ) legio diabolica ,
adjuramus te per deum , vivum per deum .
( GROWLING ) Omnis satanica potestas . "
It 's not working !
" Vivum per deum , ego te , immunde spiritus . "
( BONES CRACKING )
What ? David , wait !
Stop it ! What ? What ? !
( LOUD ROAR ) ( SCREAMING )
David ! David ! Help me , please !
What are you doing ? David !
- Help him , please ! - ( GROWLING )
David , stop it ! David ! David !
( SHRIEKING )
- Leave him alone ! - Arne , don 't talk to it .
I said , leave him alone . He 's just a little boy , you coward !
No , Arne , don 't talk to it !
( SCREAMS )
( GRUNTS )
( DEEP , GUTTURAL VOICE ) I 'll stop your heart , old man !
( GASPING FOR BREATH )
Ed ! ( SHARP GROAN )
Hey !
( GASPING )
Listen to me . Look at me .
- ( SHRIEKS ) - Look at me !
I know you 're still in there , David .
- ( GROWLS ) - Just leave him alone , okay ?
Leave him alone and take me .
Take me . Hey , take me . Take me !
David !
Leave him alone and take me !
( GROWLING STOPS )
( PANTING )
( GASPING ) No .
( EXHALES )
( BREATHLESS ) No , no .
David . David , David !
David , are you okay ? Hey , hey .
David , go with Mom .
Oh , oh !
( MOM WEEPING ) Yes , David .
( GASPING FOR BREATH )
Ed ? Ed ! Hon !
What ?
( STAMMERING )
( WHIMPERS , PANTING )
Somebody call 911 !
Okay !
( DIALING )
Oh , my God .
DOCTOR : Mrs. Warren .
He 's stabilized .
We 're gonna transfer him to the coronary unit .
- So , it was a heart attack ? - Yes .
And not a minor one , I 'm afraid .
- Can we see him now ? - Not yet .
We 're gonna to put a stent into his artery ,
try to get blood flowing back to his heart .
So , is he gonna be all right ?
We 're gonna need to run a few more tests before I 'm comfortable answering that .
I 'm sorry .
( SNIFFLING )
( ARNE , FAINTLY ) Leave him alone !
( ED , FAINTLY ) Arne , don 't talk to it !
ARNE : Leave him alone and take me .
Leave him alone !
( DAVID SCREAMING , FAINT )
( BLOW-DRYER WHIRRING , SHUTS OFF )
Hey , the mummy lives .
Hey , why did you let me sleep so late ?
( CHUCKLES ) " Let you " ? I couldn 't wake you .
- You couldn 't wake me ? - No , I couldn 't .
Oh , that 's strange .
You mustn 't have been trying very hard .
No .
( MOANS SOFTLY )
- ( DOGS BARKING OUTSIDE ) - MAN : Buddy !
- Easy , easy , easy ! - Okay , Bruno is right outside .
Oh , come on . Bruno 's a worldly man ,
- he doesn 't care . ( LAUGHING )
No .
No , no , wait . Actually , I do want to ask you something .
Okay . What do you want to ask me ?
Um ...
- It 's no big deal . - Mm-hm .
- I 've I 've been thinking ... - Mm-hm .
And now David 's out of the woods , maybe ...
we should put all this behind us and get out of this place .
- You know ? - You mean , leave Brookfield ?
Sure , why not ? We 've got nothing keeping us here now .
Oh , yeah , nothing but my family
and all the money we don 't have . Arne ...
Okay , well , money 's no big deal , right ?
We 're both working , and this place doesn 't cost us anything .
Arne , I just started this job .
I can 't just up and walk out now .
- BRUNO : Jesus Christ ! - And besides ,
Bruno doesn 't know the first thing about taking care of these dogs .
Hey ...
Let me think about it . Okay ?
- You 'll think about it ? - Yeah , I 'll think about it .
Okay . There we go .
( CHUCKLES ) Okay , get dressed .
SINGSONG : I love you !
( EDDIE MONEY : " BABY HOLD ON " PLAYING )
GIRL : I think David will love that .
- Did you call my mom ? - ARNE : Yeah , I did .
- I told her we were going to be very late . - Okay , thank you .
No , Arne . Please stop eating , please stop .
Mrs. Haskett , so good to see you , thanks for coming by .
- MRS. HASKETT : Bye . - Hey , we 're headed out now .
BRUNO : Bye , Pookie !
I wrote down a list of stuff for you to do while we 're gone .
Oh ! Keeping track of this stuff is what I 'm supposed to be paying you for .
Not on weekends , you 're not .
I 'm letting you live here rent free .
That should buy me the weekends , maybe the holidays , too .
Okay , Andy gets one cup , everyone else gets two .
Magic and Sparky are getting picked up , 50 you don 't need to worry about them .
But , you 'll have to take everyone else outside at some point this afternoon .
Oh , Ruby 's allergic to bees ,
if she gets stung you 've got to call the emergency vet .
I wrote the number down and stuck it on the fridge .
- ( MUSIC DISTORTS ) - Yo , Arne !
You wanna make a quick five bucks , man ?
My stereo 's busted .
Uh , yeah , sure . I 'll take a look at it later .
But , um , make it 15 .
Ten .
- GIRL : ... what happened this morning . - MOM : I know .
- Ma , okay . Please don 't say anything . - I won 't say anything , I promise .
Just ...
He asked if we could leave Brookfield .
( GASPS ) You know what that means , don 't you ?
No .
- Actually , you mean he proposed ? - ( LAUGHING ) Not exactly .
- Did you say , yes ? - Not exactly .
Arne ! Can you bring out the tray with the meat on it ?
Oh , yes . I 'm starving ! Are you starving , bud ?
Yeah .
Okay , I 'll go get the meat .
Ow ! ( LAUGHS )
( DOOR SHUTS )
( BOX RATTLING )
( CEREAL SCATTERING )
( SQUEAKS )
( GASPING )
( PANTING )
( WOMAN OVER P.A. ) Doctor Merrick , to OR-6 .
( SOFT KNOCK )
It was nice seeing Judy again .
Mm .
Will she be staying long ?
I don 't know , uh , it depends if ...
The nurse says that you have been sleeping in that chair .
( SIGHS )
Ed would understand if you went home for a little while .
Did I ever tell you the story of how we met ?
No , I don 't think so .
Just that you were young . In high school , wasn 't it ?
Yeah . We were seventeen .
I went out with my girlfriends and ...
And he was an usher at the movie theater that we went to .
Afterwards ...
we went out for ice cream .
He took me out to the park , but then it started to rain .
And , we stood under the gazebo until it stopped .
That was 30 years ago .
I could go back to the house , Father ...
but my home is here with him .
( MEN CHATTERING FAINTLY OUTSIDE )
( MOTOR SPUTTERING )
( MOTOR ROARING )
Jesus Christ , Arne ! What the hell ?
( PANTING )
( DOGS BARKING )
BRUNO : Can we please do something about this racket ?
These dogs are driving me crazy !
GIRL : They probably just smell a rabbit or something .
- How come you 're not at work ? - I wasn 't feeling so hot .
( BRUNO LAUGHING ) Arne ! Perfect timing , man .
Hey , why don 't you come inside with me , have a beer .
If we get that stereo fixed , we can put up a sign ,
- close up shop . - Bruno .
You know what , I don 't think so , Bruno .
Come on . Why , you quit drinking ?
No , I just don 't ...
Tell you what , we can both quit next Saturday .
How about that ? ( LAUGHS )
( DOGS CONTINUE BARKING )
- ( MONITOR BEEPING ) - ( OXYGEN HISSING )
( WHISPERING ) Lorraine . Lorraine .
- Lorraine . - Daddy !
Oh , Ed , thank God .
Lorraine .
- You have to call the Glatzels . - She just called , you 're fine .
We have to warn them , it 's got the kid .
No , it 's fine , it 's over . David is safe , the demon is gone .
Arne . It 's got Arne !
( BLONDIE ; " CALL ME " PLAYING )
It 's beautiful , man . Nicely done !
Come on , man , don 't make me drink alone .
Your girl 's gonna think I 'm a drunk .
Do you know ...
that I saw these guys play in Sydney ?
They nearly blew the roof off Her Majesty 's Theater !
Bruno ! Can you turn that down ?
I 'm testing out his work !
( TURNS UP VOLUME )
( PHONE RINGING )
( MUSIC CONTINUES , MUFFLED )
( LINE RINGING )
( SWIRLING , DISEMBODIED WHISPERS )
( SOUNDS FADE )
( SHORT , RAGGED BREATHING )
( DOGS BARKING FAINTLY )
- ( SOUNDS RETURN ) - Ame ! What 's the matter ?
Are you okay ? Bruno ...
- Let 's dance , brother ! - Bruno ! No , stop !
- Bruno . Bruno ! - ( RECORD SKIPS )
Oh , my Lord ... Okay . Bruno , go night-night .
- No ! Not until we dance . - Yes ! No , we 're not dancing .
- One dance ! One dance ! - I don 't want to dance ! Bruno !
Okay , one dance .
- ( NOISE SLOWS DOWN ) - ( LAUGHTER ECHOING )
( PHONE RINGING )
- This is Officer Thomas . - My name is Lorraine Warren .
I know how this is gonna sound ,
but there 's gonna be a tragedy at the Brookfield Boarding Kennels .
( MUSIC CONTINUES LOUDLY )
( SOUNDS FADE )
( MUSIC DISTORTS , FADES )
( GIRL SCREAMING )
Debbie !
( DEBBIE SHRIEKS )
- Arne ... - Bruno ?
No , stop .
Arne !
- ( EXHALES ) - ( BRUNO GRUNTING )
Bruno , stop !
Arne , help me .
( LOUD ROAR ) ( SCREAMING )
- Ame , whoa . What is going on ? - ( MUSIC RESUMES , LOUDLY )
- What are you doing ? - ( ARNE SCREAMS )
Arne , please stop it !
( FRANTIC BARKING )
Baby ?
What the hell ?
( MUSIC SLOWS , DISTORTING )
( MUSIC STOPS SUDDENLY )
( GUTTURAL GROWLING )
( ARNE SCREAMS )
( KNIFE SLASHING )
( SCREAMS , GROWLING CONTINUE )
DEBBIE : No , stop !
( SHUFFLING FOOTSTEPS )
( POLICE SIREN WHOOPS )
( FAINT RADIO CHATTER )
Hey .
You okay there ?
You okay ?
Now , you just stay right there , okay ? Don 't move .
I think I hurt someone .
( MAN , OVER RADIO ) This is Sergeant Thomas .
I have one victim down , multiple stab wounds .
FEMALE TV REPORTER : Residents of Brookfield were shocked this afternoon
by the broad daylight murder of Bruno Sauls .
Sauls , the manager of a local dog kennel ,
was stabbed 22 times .
This is the first murder in that town 's 193-year history .
ARNE : " Who shall ascend into the hill of the Lord ?
Or who shall stand in his holy place ?
He that hath clean hands , and a pure heart ;
Who hath not lifted up his soul unto vanity ,
nor sworn deceitfully .
He shall receive the blessing from the Lord ,
and righteousness from the God of his salvation . "
Right . That 's enough . Thank you .
Well ?
These religious objects would 've been enough
to provoke an inhuman spirit ,
if there was one present .
Does that mean he 's ... not possessed ?
The fact that he can read from the Bible just seals it .
So , w-what does this mean , then ?
I 'm just crazy ?
Well ... ( EXHALES ) you 're not possessed .
But , that doesn 't mean that you weren 't .
I ... invited this thing into me ,
and that 's the reason that he 's dead .
So , you know , whatever happens to me , I 've got it coming .
No , you don 't .
Look ...
I was there .
Whatever is going on ...
Whatever happened that day ...
That was not Arne .
We 're gonna help you in every way that we can .
If the demon 's gone , what can you do now ?
Who 's your lawyer ?
He was found covered in the victim 's blood .
The murder weapon belongs to him and it 's got his fingerprints all over it .
Nobody 's disputing any of that . Arne knows that he 's going to prison .
All we 're saying is that there were mitigating circumstances .
Mitigating circumstances ?
Look , I don 't think he should get the death sentence , either .
But I am not going before a grand jury
and saying he was possessed by demons .
- It 's never been done . - Yes it has !
It 's been done twice in England .
The Michael Taylor case was just a few years ago .
All right , let me rephrase that .
It 's never been done successfully .
Then let us help you .
Ed and I have proven the existence of the demonic hundreds of times .
You 've proven it to the Church . This is a court of law .
The standards of evidence are completely different .
The courts accepts the existence of God
every time a witness swears to tell the truth .
I think it 's about time they accept the existence of the Devil .
( SIGHS )
How are you going to convince a jury if you can 't even convince me ?
Well , I 'll tell you what . You come over to our house for dinner .
We 'll show you the evidence we 've collected over the years .
Introduce you to Annabelle .
If you 're not convinced , we 'll butt out .
Deal ?
( EXHALES )
All right . Show me what you got .
( GAVEL BANGING )
Mr. Johnson , to count one of indictment number S-A-J ...
one-two-one-six , which charges you with first-degree murder ,
a class-A felony ,
how do you plead ?
Your Honor , my client pleads not guilty ...
by reason of demonic possession .
( BELL TOLLING )
This is ridiculous . I can walk down a flight of stairs .
Oh , hush . You shouldn 't even be out of bed .
Lorraine .
I just talked to a friend of mine in the prosecutor 's office .
He 's gonna go for the death penalty .
I 'll build the case , but that kid is gonna either live or die
depending on what you two find .
Well , we won 't let him down .
I hope not .
Keep me posted .
So , what now ?
We 've never had to prove a possession after the fact .
Demons don 't just disappear like this .
There 's something else going on here ,
something that we missed the first time .
Where do we start ?
At the beginning .
ED : Its July 18th , 1981 .
This is Ed Warren , here with Lorraine ...
and Judy Glatzel , Deborah Glatzel ,
David Glatzel and Arne Johnson .
All right , let 's get started .
Who was there when David first started exhibiting this behavior ?
JUDY : We all were . It was the day we moved in .
There you go . Go have fun with them .
- JUDY : Wanna order some pizza ? - DEBBIE : Yeah sure , I 'll do that right now .
- DEBBIE : Hey . - ARNE : Put that box down a second .
- Why ? - I just ... I just ...
What are you doing ?
- Have a look ... - What is ... ( LAUGHING ) Arne !
You know you 're supposed to do this when you get married ?
Okay , so maybe we 'll do that too .
Oh .
( DEBBIE SHRIEKS , LAUGHING )
( HINGES CREAKING )
( WATER SLOSHING )
( WATER RIPPLING )
( SCREAMING )
( SHRIEKING )
No !
Mom !
( PANTING )
( DAVID , ON TAPE ) I didn 't know what happened .
It was like a dream .
And nobody believed me when I told them .
But that was the first time I saw if .
( SIGHS )
DEBBIE : I don 't get it .
How could he have invited a demon ? He was only in here for a few minutes .
There wasn 't even anything in here .
Where was the water bed ?
Where that rug is .
The wood got damaged when the mattress ruptured .
Mind if I have a look ? Please .
( GROANING SOFTLY )
( INHALES )
That 's not water damage .
Hon , will you let me handle this ?
You 're gonna ruin your dress if you go in there .
So , um ... the guest room 's about 15 feet in and to the right .
Okay .
- Just be careful . - Just hold my purse .
- ( SHRIEKS ) - Lorraine ? ! Are you all right ?
Yeah , I 'm fine , Ed . It 's just a rat .
( BOTH SIGHING )
( FAINT SCUTTLING )
( SQUEAKING )
( BREATHING HEAVILY )
( RATS SQUEAKING )
( SCREAMING )
( WHISPERING ) In manus tuas , Domine commendo spiritum meum .
LORRAINE : It 's a witch 's totem , used by satanists in their rituals .
Remember how I told you that an inhuman spirit needs to be invited ?
And you couldn 't imagine how David could do that ?
Well , you were right , he didn 't .
We think David was cursed .
And on the night of the exorcism ,
the curse was passed from David into Arne .
Cursed ?
Are you saying someone did this to us ... on purpose ?
We 've heard of satanic rituals like this . The demon is summoned ,
the possessed individual takes a life and the demon departs .
Which is why Arne was able to read from the Bible afterwards .
Yeah . We think whoever cursed David , used this to draw the demon .
And we 'd like you to start mailing these out
to every police department you can find .
Start locally .
And , just find out if they 've ever seen anything like this .
There might be someone else we can ask about this .
Do you remember the priest
who helped expose the Disciples of the Ram cult ?
It would 've been about ten , twelve years ago ...
- Father Kästner ? - Yeah , you 're right .
Only it isn 't " Father " anymore . He 's been retired for a while .
He tried to help those people .
He tried to understand why they did what they did .
If anyone is going to be able to tell us what this is , it 's him .
( CHICKENS CLUCKING )
Father Kästner .
I didn 't hear the car drive in .
Would either of you care for an omelet ?
We had breakfast before we left home .
I 'm Ed Warren , this is my wife Lorraine .
I have chicken shit on my hands .
( BOTH CHUCKLING )
LORRAINE : Thank you .
Forget you ever saw this .
You 've seen it before ?
No . But , I 've seen ones like it .
This is sophisticated . It 's a very nasty piece of work .
What I don 't understand is ... is why ?
David , the little boy who was possessed ,
he ... he didn 't do anything wrong .
Why would someone target this family ?
Why ?
The " why " is irrelevant .
The " why " is counter to everything that the satanist stands for .
His sole aim is chaos .
His nectar is despair .
But someone had to put it under their house .
So , what does this tell you about the person who made it ?
Come with me .
I don 't want to go down there .
( DOOR UNLATCHES )
What is this ?
It 's the reason you 're here .
( HINGES CREAK LOUDLY )
( KÄSTNER ) I collected these while I was studying
the Disciples of the Ram .
- You should burn all this . - I 've thought of it .
But I felt it was safer to keep them locked .
I like taking guns off the streets .
I don 't suppose you have all these books organized
using the Dewey Decimal System , do you ?
No . ( CHUCKLES SOFTLY ) No . No , I do not .
The clues you seek could be anywhere . Or they ...
Or they may not be here at all .
Ed , don 't .
( KÄSTNER ) I studied these people for nine years .
They worshipped Satan and his demons with blood sacrifice .
They defiled holy land with their obscene rituals , and ...
they committed acts of blasphemy ... which I shall never speak of .
But ... these acts gave them power .
The trial of the Disciples ,
the lead prosecutor ... his wife was pregnant .
A few days after the Disciples were all found guilty ,
his baby was born six weeks early , with its heart outside of its body .
Three months later , his wife committed suicide
by laying her neck on a railroad track .
A master satanist is not an adversary to be taken lightly .
We know the dangers , better than you might think .
This boy who 's headed to the death chamber ...
Is saving him worth everything you have ?
Because that 's what it may very well cost .
( FEEDBACK SQUEALS OVER SPEAKER )
So , you gonna clean it up , or what ?
Sorry .
- ( BUCKET CLATTERS ) - ( GASPS )
( WHISPERING ) What ?
( SINGING ) Color me your color , darling
I know who you are .
Come up off your color chart .
I know where you 're coming from
( FAINT CHUCKLE )
I know who you are
( SCREAMING )
( WHIMPERING )
It was here ! I swear to God , it was here !
( FOOTSTEPS ON STONE )
( RAVEN CALLING )
Look what the Perron family sent .
- Oh , that was sweet of them . - Mmm .
( PHONE RINGING )
- Got it . - Ed , let me .
It 's okay , it 's okay , it 's okay .
- Hello ? - Ed ? We 've got a bite .
I just got off the phone with a homicide detective in Danvers .
He wants to talk to you guys . He says he 's seen it .
Katie Lincoln and Jessica Strong went missing about four months ago .
They were best friends in high school .
Katie 's body was found near here , stabbed 22 times .
We still haven 't found Jessica .
But when we searched her home back in May ...
we found this .
So , you 're the experts .
What can you tell me about this ?
Well , to be honest , not much .
Only that if this totem works the same way as the one in Brookfield ,
it 's possible that your missing girl was possessed .
Look , I 've read all about what you two think happened in Brookfield .
But I 'm only interested in leads that are grounded in reality .
Good . So are we .
We were actually hoping there might be something in this case file
that might help prove Arne 's story .
No , no , no . I brought you here to help me ,
not the other way around .
Now , we 've been looking for a link to some sort of
satanic cult ever since we found that thing .
And these devil worshippers , they 're just people .
Crazy , evil people , but , people .
Maybe we can help each other .
We need to see your case file ...
and you need to find the missing girl .
So , give us a chance .
- To do what exactly ? - To find Jessica .
We 've been combing through these forests for over three months now , Mrs. Warren .
I can see things that your people can 't .
( SIGHS )
One of these is the knife used on Katie Lincoln .
The others I just pulled from the evidence locker .
And what ? You want her to pick out the murder weapon ?
Mm-hm .
I 'll take you out there , but first I want to see what she can do .
Absolutely not ! My wife 's gift is not a sideshow attraction .
If she is what you say she is ,
then this shouldn 't be a problem , Mr. Warren . Right ?
- No way ! Forget it . We ... - It 's this one .
( ELVIS PRESLEY : " SUSPICIOUS MINDS " PLAYING )
It was a one-in-three chance .
( CHUCKLES LIGHTLY )
This song 's appropriate .
You know , I actually met Elvis once .
- Oh , yeah ? - Mm-hm .
Was that before or after he died ? Before ...
and after .
You missed a turn .
The spot where you found Katie 's body , it was back that way .
DEBBIE : They 're in Danvers right now .
If they can find some way to connect what happened there
to what happened to you , then ...
You know , it 's ... it 's a pattern .
They might even find out who did this .
Okay . Well , that sounds great , right ?
- It 's great . - Baby ...
What 's going on ?
Nothing .
I 'm fine , I 'm tired , you know ...
Come on .
You 're keeping something from me .
Don 't you think I can tell that ?
Look , I 'm fine . Totally fine .
It 's cold in here .
Yeah , right ?
It 's like , uh ...
It 's like they 're trying to freeze us out , or something .
I remember what it felt like .
You 're always cold , and you 're never alone .
David , what are you talking about ?
That 's why you can 't sleep . Because it 's never quiet in your head .
Sometimes you think something ,
then you 're not sure if it was really you .
But now you 're seeing it .
It 's here with you . And it 's telling you to do things .
Arne , what is it telling you to do ?
You sure you should be tromping through the woods like this ?
Yeah , I 'm fine .
Then what are you worried about ? Afraid she won 't be able to do it ?
( ED CHUCKLES DRYLY )
No .
I 'm afraid that she will .
Ed , something terrible happened here .
( BRANCHES CREAKING )
( FAINT RUSTLING ) ( GASPS LIGHTLY )
( FAINT SCRATCHING )
( LAUGHTER )
( ED PANTING )
JESSICA : Katie , wait up .
( KATIE LAUGHS )
Hey .
Um , I got you something .
They were selling them at the May Festival this year .
Your parents still dragging you up there for that ?
Every year , since I was six .
( BOTH LAUGHING )
It 's dumb , but ... I thought this was cool .
It reminded me of the ones we made in high school .
Will you help me put it on ?
Sure .
( PANTING )
( GASPS )
( GASPING )
All right , that 's enough .
Hon , that 's enough .
- That 's enough ! Come on ! - ( GASPS )
( LORRAINE PANTING )
Oh , Katie ? Katie ?
Oh , my God . What did I do ?
Hon , no ! Oh !
Lorraine !
( JESSICA GASPING , SOBBING )
( PANTING )
( GASPING FOR BREATH )
( SOBBING )
( PANTING )
ED : Lorraine !
Lorraine .
( SOBS ) Ed .
ED : No ! ( SCREAMING )
No !
( BOTH YELLING )
( ED GRUNTING )
- ( BREATHING HEAVILY ) - It 's okay . I got you .
( LORRAINE GASPING LOUDLY )
She 's down there . Ed , she 's down there .
WOMAN : Blood pressure 's a little high .
I 'm gonna give you a vasodilator .
It 's a pill , you 're gonna put it under your tongue .
It 'll open up your blood vessels .
Yeah , I have those .
I left them at home .
PARAMEDIC : Yeah , well , I wouldn 't do that anymore if I were you .
Mind giving us a minute ?
Recovery team found a body .
- As it ... ? - We 're not sure .
Look , I know what it looks like .
But , I don 't want any of this getting out
until we have a positive ID from the coroner .
You know , we dragged this basin . Twice .
Had to pull teeth to get it done a third time .
We never would 've done it if it weren 't for you .
I 'm just glad we could help .
Let me know where you 're staying .
And I 'll get that case file to you in the morning .
( CAR DOORS OPENING )
( PHONE RINGING )
( ED EXHALES HEAVILY )
Hello ?
Oh , my God , I 've been leaving messages all day .
- What 's wrong ? - It 's Arne . If followed him !
You said this was over ,
but now he 's trapped in there with this thing
and it 's telling him to kill himself !
Debbie . Just calm down and listen to me .
I need you to call the prison chaplain , um ...
- ( SNAPS FINGERS ) - Father Newman .
Father Newman . Tell him that ...
Arne needs to be put on a 24-hour suicide watch !
- He 's got ... - ( HARSH , RASPING FEEDBACK )
- ( DIAL TONE ) - What ? Hello ?
What is this thing ?
( ROLLING THUNDERCLAP )
( KEYS JINGLING )
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( DOOR LOCK CLANKS )
FATHER NEWMAN : Arne .
God gives everyone the right to defend themselves .
( THUNDERCLAP )
( HATCH THUDS , LOCKS )
LORRAINE : This demon ...
It 's not here of its own free will . It was summoned .
That doesn 't make me feel any better .
That means , we know that this is a curse ,
and curses can be broken .
All right . Then how do we do that ?
Back at the Glatzel house ,
I touched David 's hand and I saw something .
I didn 't know what it was then .
But I think that I was connected to the person who is responsible for this .
Ed , that body they found ...
If it 's Jessica , if it 's really her ...
then that connection could still be open .
There 's gotta be another way .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
( FOOTSTEPS THUDDING )
- ( ARNE PANTING ) - ( KEYS JINGLING )
Okay ... okay .
Okay .
ARNE : The Lord is my shepherd ;
There is nothing I shall want .
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures ...
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
There 's nobody there .
We 'll leave a note .
( LATCH CLICKS )
( HINGES CREAKING )
( DOOR THUDS CLOSED )
( DOOR CREAKS )
( TIMER SWITCH TICKING )
Oh , boy .
( SIGHING )
( EXHALES )
Please be careful .
( QUIET WHIMPER )
Oh .
( SIGHS DEEPLY )
Do you see anything ?
No . There 's nothing .
There 's nothing here .
I 'm not sensing it .
- Lorraine , what is it ? - ( WHISPERING ) The connection .
It 's here .
( WATER DRIPPING )
( MUFFLED TRAIN HORN BLOWING )
( TRAIN CLATTERING FAINTLY )
ED : Do you see anything ?
Yes .
Yes , there are ... some stairs .
I heard a train .
But now ... ( EXHALES )
There 's an altar .
( MATCH STRIKING )
All those black candles .
There 's 12 of them . In a circle .
- Oh , Ed . - Okay , that 's enough , come back .
I can 't .
Lorraine .
( SWITCH TICKING )
It 's a woman .
ED : Can you see her ?
LORRAINE : I am her .
Can you tell where she is ?
I don 't know . I ...
She 's doing it again .
She 's reaching out to Arne .
She 's trying to complete the curse .
( GASPS )
( BOTTLE SHATTERS )
LORRAINE : Oh , she has him . She has Arne .
Oh , no , no .
No , no . Oh , God .
End this black Sabbath .
By the blood of Calvary I command it !
( LORRAINE GRUNTING )
( EXHALES )
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
I got a cutter ! C-19 !
Come on , kid .
How are you doing this ?
God has shown you to me .
Then your God has damned you .
Ed . The connection works both ways .
Lorraine .
You need to come back .
- Lorr ... - ( BONES CRACKING )
Lorraine ?
You need to break the connection .
Drop ... her hand .
Lorraine , let go of her hand .
( INHALES )
( GROWLS )
( BOTH PANTING )
Ed ...
She knows who we are .
( THUNDER RUMBLING )
- ( SIGHS ) - LORRAINE : We are so sorry .
- ( DEBBIE CRYING ) - Oh , we 're so sorry .
How 's Arne ?
He 'll be all right . They got him sedated .
We got the case file .
There 's got to be something here that connects these girls back to him .
That 's great .
I got something to show you , too .
I found it in the Stregheria . It 's early Renaissance .
The Church used it to identify and persecute witchcraft .
Now ...
My Latin is rusty , but , I think this ...
is talking about a human sacrifice .
One by murder and the other by suicide .
Does it say how to stop it ?
Yeah , it looks like ...
you can break the curse by destroying the altar it was cast from .
But ... this part looks like Aramaic .
This next part ... eh , I can 't read it .
But you stopped her . Maybe she 'll give up now .
She can 't .
Once started , the curse must be completed .
Her soul depends on it .
We 'll find another way .
Was there anything in your vision that might help us find her altar ?
It was cold .
There was water dripping from the ceiling .
Uh ... I think I heard a train .
But it sounded strange somehow . Like , um ...
I don 't know , uh , muffled ?
Well , maybe it was underground .
Could be . I don 't know where .
This woman targeted David and Jessica .
Maybe there 's a connection there . Let me take a look at the ...
( VOICE LOOPING ) take a look at the ... take a look at the ...
file .
( THUNDER BOOMING )
( GROANS LIGHTLY )
Lorraine ?
( LEAVES RUSTLING IN WIND FAINTLY )
Lorraine !
( PANTING )
( WHISPERS ) No .
( BOOK PAGE TURNING )
Where is she ?
You know , the two of you have gathered quite the collection .
If you hurt her ...
Oh , don 't worry , Mr. Warren .
You 're so close .
I 'd hate for you to give up now .
( CANE THUDS LOUDLY )
( MUFFLED THUD )
( THUD REPEATS )
( DOOR CREAKING OPEN )
( ROARING )
( GRUNTS )
- ( THUDDING FOOTSTEPS ) - ( GROWLING )
( SHRIEKS )
He who calls forth the water of the sea !
The Lord of Hosts is His name !
Deliver Thy servant from all the workings of unclean spirits !
Fear and flee , unclean spirit !
Ed ! ( LORRAINE SCREAMS )
( KNIFE CLATTERS )
Ed .
I 'm sorry .
Ed , it was her !
It was her .
DREW : Ed , what the hell is going on ?
- Help me find it ! - Find what ?
- Where is it ? - DREW : Ed .
Ed !
She was here ! She was in our house !
When did these get here ?
They just arrived yesterday while you guys were driving home .
They were fresh when they got here .
( LORRAINE GASPS )
( ED EXHALES )
( GASPING )
LORRAINE : We have to find this woman .
We 've identified the curse and now we have Jessica 's case file .
There has to be something in here .
Okay , I 'm gonna take the book to be translated .
There has to be a clue about where we can find the altar .
DEBBIE : So what do we do ?
You should go be with Arne .
He 's gonna need you tonight more than ever .
Ask Father Newman for help .
Drew , you and me are gonna tear into those files .
We 've got to find a link between these cases .
And a satanist 's power is strongest at night . So ...
let 's hope she doesn 't try anything before then .
They 've stopped his sedation .
He 'll be coming around soon .
DREW : There 's nothing in these interviews .
Her friends barely saw her after she got back from college .
Didn 't that seem strange to you ? I mean , we 're here ,
the Glatzels live here , just 15 minutes away .
But Jessica lived 180 miles from here .
Why is this one so far away ?
Hey , where did Jessica find her totem ?
I just saw something about that .
( twas in an interview with her parents . ( twas in a box .
" She brought it back home in a box from college . "
Where 'd she go to college ?
Fairfield .
This woman lives in the area .
Still a lot of ground to cover .
Yeah , but not a lot of train tracks .
Remember Lorraine 's vision ? She said she heard a train .
What time was it ? Maybe we can start eliminating some of these .
Probably close to midnight .
Then it can 't be either of these two . The commuter lines don 't run that late .
That just leaves this freight line that crosses the river here .
The river .
Oh , dear God .
( KNOCKING ON DOOR )
Mrs. Warren .
I 'm sorry , Father , we tried calling , but we couldn 't reach you .
We were hoping you 'd help us translate a passage from this book .
Of course . Come in .
Thank you .
Give me your keys . You stay here , call the police .
- What do you want me to tell them ? - Anything , just get ' em out there !
( DIALING )
( KÄSTNER ) It 's the curse .
It says , the curse needs three victims to be complete .
It refers to them as ...
" The child , the lover and the man of God . "
The embodiment of God 's work .
Purity , love , faith .
Has there been another ?
It 's Ed . It 's my husband .
Last night we found a totem in his office .
That is unfortunate .
Here , come with me .
There 's something I need to show you .
( FLOORBOARD CREAKING )
Father ?
I 've been here many years ...
starting when I was a priest .
The church used this mill for storage .
It 's where they put the things that they were afraid of .
Things they didn 't understand .
You had a child ?
Her mother died in childbirth .
The Church couldn 't know .
So I raised her here , in secret .
It was just the two of us .
Our happiness filled this house .
I continued my studies into the occult .
I wanted to protect her from all this .
But instead I created a fascination .
We must be careful ...
how our obsessions are passed to our children .
" He who dwells in the shelter of the most high ...
Will rest in the shadow of the Almighty .
I will say of the Lord , he is my refuge and my fortress ...
my God in whom I trust . "
It 's just the wiring .
You know , state building .
( ARNE WHISPERING ) Debbie .
Arne .
What is it ?
( BREATHING DEEPLY )
She 's ... she 's close .
You knew ?
We came to you for help and you knew this whole time ?
She 's my daughter .
I couldn 't ...
I didn 't want to see .
After all these years , I thought she 'd come back to me again .
And now I know the real reason she 's here .
There are tunnels under this land .
She would explore them as a child .
Her altar must be down there .
It 's the only thing that can break her curse .
We need to destroy it .
( FLOORBOARD CREAKS )
She 's here .
( KÄSTNER ) Go .
I failed as a priest .
And I failed as a father .
Please , God , don 't let me fail ...
( GAGGING )
( GROANS QUIETLY )
( PANTING )
( GRUNTING LOUDLY )
( GASPS WITH EFFORT )
( THUDDING FOOTSTEPS )
( GROANING )
( THUDDING CONTINUES )
( LORRAINE GASPS )
( BOOTS THUDDING )
Lorraine !
( LORRAINE , FAINTLY ) Ed !
( MUFFLED ) Ed ?
Ed !
Lorraine !
( YELLS )
( GRUNTS LOUDLY )
Ed !
( GASPING LOUDLY )
( SHRIEKS )
( YELLS )
( GASPS LOUDLY )
( LORRAINE PANTING )
Look at me .
Open your eyes .
WITCH : Sh-sh-sh-sh ...
Look at me .
No !
( WITCH TUTTING SOFTLY )
( LORRAINE GASPS )
WITCH : Look at me .
Open your eyes and look at me .
( WITCH TUTTING SOFTLY )
Open up .
- ( LORRAINE YELLS ) - ( WITCH GRUNTS )
( ED PANTING )
Lorraine !
Lorraine ?
Ed !
( GRUNTS )
( COUGHING )
Ed ?
( ED YELLING )
( GRUNTING LOUDLY )
( ARNE SCREAMING )
- It 's happening . - N-Now ?
Now .
" Ne memorem esse oportet , Domine , delicta nostra ... "
Vel parentum nostrorum ...
neque nostrorum ,
- vindictam sumas de " ... - ( SCREAMS )
( LORRAINE GASPS ) ( ED YELLS )
Ed , stop !
Stop ! Ed , I 'm begging you !
( YELLS )
Ed ! Stop !
( SCREAMING )
( BONES CRACKING )
( PRISON ALARM WHOOPING )
( ARNE SCREAMING )
DEBBIE : Arne !
Arne , please . It 's okay .
( SCREAMING )
FATHER NEWMAN : Our Father who art in Heaven
( GUTTURAL GROWLING )
- Hallowed be thy name ... - No , Arne . It 's okay ! Please !
Thy kingdom come , thy will be done ...
- on Earth as it is in Heaven . - Arne , it 's okay !
Stop this ! Ed , I 'm begging you !
I 'm begging you , remember me !
Stop !
( LORRAINE YELPS , GASPING )
( GRUNTS )
Ed , stop !
( LORRAINE SCREAMS )
( LORRAINE WHISPERING ) Ed , please .
Remember me .
DEBBIE : Oh , my God ! Guards !
... and lead us not into temptation ; But deliver us from evil .
- For thine is the kingdom ... - Arne , it 's okay .
The power and the glory ... ( ROARING )
Now and forever , Amen !
Our Father , who art in Heaven , hallowed be thy name ;
Thy kingdom come , thy will be done ...
- on Earth as it is in Heaven . - No , Arne !
Arne ? Arne , what are you doing ?
( FATHER NEWMAN CONTINUES PRAYING )
What are you doing ? Stop it !
What are you doing ? Father Newman , help him !
( FATHER NEWMAN CONTINUES PRAYING )
Please ... Guards !
Please ! Stop it !
- Please help him ! - ( ARNE SCREAMING )
LORRAINE : You 're not gonna do this !
This is wrong and you know it !
( YELLS )
( SHOUTING PRAYER )
DEBBIE : Father Newman ... No , no .
What 's happening ?
Please , Father , make it stop !
( SOBBING )
( RAGGED SCREAM )
Our Father , who art in Heaven , hallowed be thy name ;
Thy kingdom come ...
No , no , no ! Arne , no !
Arne , stop , please ! Stop it !
Don 't do this , Arne , I love you !
- No ... - And lead us not into temptation ,
but deliver us from evil !
- ( ED YELLS ) - ( LORRAINE SCREAMS )
( GASPING )
Ed ... Remember me .
LORRAINE : She fried to turn you against me .
Because , she thinks our love is our weakness .
( NO AUDIBLE DIALOGUE )
( BREATH SHAKING )
LORRAINE : But it 's not .
( WHISPERING ) It 's not .
It 's our strength .
Now , open your eyes .
( LOW RUMBLING )
( LOUD THUDDING )
Arne ? Arne , are you okay ?
- ( ARNE GROANS ) - Oh , my God !
( WEEPING ) Oh , my God .
( ED GROANS )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Your curse is broken .
( KNIFE CLATTERS ) ( CRYING OUT )
- ( SCREAMS ) - ( BONES CRACKING )
You promised the demon a soul .
( YELLS IN AGONY )
( WHIMPERING )
And it can 't go back to Hell without one .
( BOOTS THUDDING )
( WHIMPERING )
( ROARS )
( ED PANTING )
DEBBIE : Oh , my God .
ARNE : It 's okay . It 's over .
Please say it 's over ...
( ED PANTING , WHEEZING )
Hon ... 1 , uh ...
I forgot my pills .
( DISTANT SIRENS APPROACHING )
( VAN MORRISON : " BRAND NEW DAY " PLAYING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
( REPORTERS CLAMORING )
DEBBIE : Arne ?
Arne ?
Excuse me . Arne !
I love you .
BAILIFF : Will the defendant please rise ?
LORRAINE : Oh !
( BOTH LAUGHING )
As we go hack now , listen to the tapes
as well as being there and hearing him do it ,
he would constantly challenge what was in that boy .
What does that do
- to the whole system of law ... - ED : Yes .
If a person can walk in and say , " The devil made me do it ? "
( DAVID SCREECHING )
LORRAINE : David , I 'm going to put this on you .
ED : In the name of Jesus , Jesus repels you .
Leave this child alone .
It 's on your forehead .
( DAVID GROWLS , INDISTINCT )
Yes , remember , you are not strong , you 're weak .
You 're weak .
Jesus loves this boy . This is ... this is His child .
JUDY : Wake him out of it . Prop him up . Do something !
DEBBIE : He won 't get out of it right now , Ma .
ARNE : He told me , he ain 't gonna do nothing now .
DEBBIE : Well , what do you think we 've been doing all this time ?
ED : In the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit , Amen !
ARNE : You gotta hold him down . He told me to .
- Hold him on the ground . - ( DAVID GROWLING )
JUDY : Mommy 's here . Mommy 's here . Come on , wake up .
Come on . Get up . Come on , let 's go .
Get out . Get out of my son .
Get out of my son . Come on .
Come on , son . Come on . Get out . Get away from my son .
( DAVID GROWLING ) Go on ! No !
I 'm your mother !
No , you 're ... ( RASPING LAUGHTER )
JUDY : David . David . Wake up !
ED : Let the boy out .
LORRAINE : Look , you need to hold him .
ED : In the name of the Father and the Son and of the Holy Spirit .
Amen .
JUDY : Do something . Sit him up .
- DEBBIE : If won 't work . - ARNE : You can 't sit him up , he 's ...
It won 't work .
( DAVID GROWLS , LAUGHING )
JUDY : David ! Please , get up !
My God , get up !